I would like to thank Cleveland
people.com for providing this wonderful
evening that honors those who have made
significant contributions in preserving
Cleveland's cultural
diversity. It's my pleasure today to
introduce Mr.
Ship Ship left India for the United
States in
1956. He's one of the pioneers of the
Indian community in Cleveland.
He arrived here with a master's degree
in social work to pursue an MBA from the
University of
Missouri. Attending that, he worked
briefly in Chicago and moved to
Cleveland, Ohio in 1958.
In the early
1960s, Shu was active in the Bakai
woodland area, helping recent immigrants
from Hungary, Slovenia, and
Italy. Many of those immigrants had
special skills but could not speak
English very well. But she taught them
English and citizenship
classes. By using his professional skill
and organization
leadership, he should help to facilitate
the turning point for many European
immigrants as they made Cleveland, Ohio
their
home. In
1966, Cleveland was in the national
spotlight with increasing racial
tensions and gang
violence. The ship took a leading role
to curb the gang violence in the Holland
area, putting himself in danger and at
the cost of his own
life. He founded Collingwood Youth
Association and helped young adults to
take up constructive
activities. In 1967, Colinwood Youth
Association grew to accommodate the
needs of seniors and came to be known as
Cottonwood Community Services
Center. This was the largest
neighborhood-based mandai service center
in
Cleveland. By the way, ship is not yet
done serving the community. He is in the
planning state of a nonprofit mobile
clinic for the elderly.
This would be a big opportunity for
seniors to receive healthcare in their
own
homes. Above all, ship is a humble
unassuming person who has dedicated his
whole life to make a difference in this
world. I consider him as a friend and a
mentor.
Sh Agarwal has been recognized for his
community involvement by three
mayors
Ralphburg George Bonovich and the
current mayor Frank
Jackson. Now ladies and gentlemen with
great honor I wish to induct
Shu into the Cleveland International
Hall of Fame 2015.
[Applause]